[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
And so, let's actually compute TF/IDF.
让我们真正着手计算TF/IDF
Now, I can't just compute TF/IDF and this is an important note by the way.
现在 我无法只计算TF/IDF 顺便提一下 这是一个重要的注意点
Can't just compute TF/IDF for
我们没法单独计算
the Obama article in isolation because tf/idf depends on entire corpus.
奥巴马文章的TF/IDF 是因为TF/IDF 取决于整个文集
You need that normalizer which is the number of times a word appears in
你需要把那些出现在每篇文章中的单词标准化
So, I have to show it I have computed for the entire corpus.
我证明给你看 我已经在整个文集中计算过了
So let's go ahead and do just that.
现在让我们开始做这个吧
So here we go, so
开始吧！
I'm gonna compute
我会计算
TF/IDF for the corpus.
整个文集的TF-IDF
And I'm gonna do this in two steps.
我会分两步来做
First, I'm gonna compute the word counts for the entire corpus.
首先我要计算整个文集中 各个单词的数量
So, I'm gonna add a new column to the people table called word_count.
所以我在people 中添加一列叫做单词计数(word_count)
Remember we just did this only for Barack Obama, so now, we're gonna do it for
我们之前对奥巴马做过类似的 现在我们要对所有人做这个
everyone.
所以我要调出graphlab.text_analytics.count_words 这个函数
I'm going got put in the input,
然后写下输入值
which is gonna be the the text column.
输入值会是text这一列
In other words, I'm gonna count the words in the text column.
换句话说 我会对text 这一列的进行单词计数
And just so that we're clear.
为了以防混淆
Then you just print the SFrame people after we do this,
我们直接打印出people
so I'm gonna print the first few lines of that SFrame.
所以我会打印出people的前几列
So here we are, we've executed.
恩 我们执行了代码
Now we have the URI column, the location, the webpage, the name of person,
你看到我们有URI 也就是网页地址这一列  人物的名字
text, and now we have this dictionary of word counts on the right, the new column.
然后在最右边 有单词计数这一列 新的一列
Good, so next we're gonna compute the TF/IDFs.
好的 下一步我们就要计算TF/IDF了
So just like with word counts, you can implement your own TF/IDF system,
就像单词计数一样 你要使用你自己的TF/IDF 系统
it will take you a little while to do.
会让你花上一些时间完成
So, Graphlocate one already implemented, and
Graphlocate已经准备就绪了
we're just gonna use that to make this whole process pretty quick,
我们准备使用这个来让整个过程变得简单一些
so we're gonna call graphlab.text_analytics.
所以我会调用graphlab.text_analytics这个函数
Just like with word count, there's a function here, .tf_idf.
就像之前调用单词计数一样
And all you need to do is give an input,
你要做的就是 需要一个输入值
just like we're gonna give in the input the word_count.
就像我们给单词计数那个函数也赋了一个输入值一样
word_count, and it will output the TF/IDF.
然后它就会计算TF/IDF了
And let me just again show you what that looks like.
让我给你看看 最后的结果是什么样的
Oops, I did a little typo here.
额 我这边打错了个字
That should be word_count.
应该是word_count
That's call not word_counts.
不是word_counts
And now I'm going through the whole corpus,with 50,000 documents.
这样我会在整个文集中 一共50000篇文章
Computing the frequency of words, normalizing.
来计算单词的频率 并标准化
And what we end up with is a table where for every document, it calls the table
最后我们的结果会是一张表 对每篇文章
docs, it has a dictionary of TF/IDF's for each one of those documents.
有一个TF/IDF的字典
And just so that we get all this right, I'm gonna add a new column.
我们之前应该做的都是正确的 我准备再添加新的一列
To the people table, and this new column is gonna be called tfidf,
对于人物这个表格 新的一列会是叫做TF/IDF
and I'm just gonna store in there the tfidf's that I just computed.
我准备在这一列储存我们的TF/IDF的值
So it's all in one table, and it's a docs column.
这也在一个表格里面 也就是TF-IDF 这个表格doc这一列
Here we go. We just added it in.
恩 我们成功的添加了
So now we have tfidf's for every document computed and stored in there.
我们现在有了每篇文章的TF/IDF 并且储存在里面
Let's do some examination.
让我们检查一下
So here's what we gonna do,
这是我们要做的
we gonna Examine the TF-IDF for
我们要检查奥巴马这篇文章的TF-IDF
the Obama article.
我们要检查奥巴马这篇文章的TF/IDF
So just like we examined and sorted the word counts,
我们之前对于单词计数和排序 进行了检查
we're not gonna examine sorting the TF ideas.
我们也会把TF-IDF的值进行排序
I'm gonna reread the variable for Obama,
所以我会重新读取奥巴马的变量
because we now added these two new columns in the latest version of that.
在最新的版本中 我们新添加了两列
So I'm gonna take people, and I'm gonna select out of the people, the one whose
所以我会选择people中
name is equal to Barack Obama.
people等于Barack Obama的那些行
Okay, I've done it, I've created this Obama, and now, just like we did with word
所以我创建了一个奥巴马 就像我们之前单词计数里做过的一样
counts, I will create an obama_tfidf_table so that we can sort it too.
我创建了一个obama_tfidf_table 然后可以进行排序
It's a dictionary.
这是一个字典
We're just gonna sort to the exactly the same way as we did before.
我们要做和之前一样的
We will stack it and then sort it.
先存储然后再排序
And we're gonna do this.
这就是我们要做的
Actually, instead of create a table, I'm just gonna do it in one line.
实际上 我不会再建立一个表格 而是在一行内搞定它
Oops, I'm gonna do just in one line here.
我要一行完成
So I'm gonna write out what we did earlier, so
所以我的代码就是
I'm gonna just take the obama variable and
我选取
when I select only the tfidf column so it looks a little prettier.
奥巴马中tf-idf这一列 这样看起来会漂亮些
Then I'm gonna call the stack method, which takes a dictionary and
然后.stack 这个指令可以把字典中我想要的
just stacks it into two columns.
分成两列
So I'm gonna stack tfidf.
所以我要存储tf-idf的值
And I'm going to output new column names and
所以输出值的新两列的名字会是
those names are going to be the word and
word 和 tf-idf
the tfidf, and let me show you something.
让我给你看些新的东西
Ooops, I, Forgot to close, click it here.
不好 我这边忘记加引号了
And let me show you a little neat trick that you can use with Python in
让我给你看一点python的小技巧
various ways.
很有用的小技巧
I'm just gonna chain the source comment at the end of this.
我会在这行代码的末尾加上一些指令
So I'm just gonna type .sort.
比如说.sort
And I'm gonna sort this output on the tfidf column.
这样我就会对tf-idf这一列进行排序
And I'm gonna say ascending=false.
然后我输入 asceding=false 进行降序排列
So what I did in multiple lines before, now I'm doing it in just one line.
所以说我之前用了很多行代码 现在我用一行代码就搞定了
I'm taking the obama column tfidf.
这样我就收集到了奥巴马的tf-idf这一列
I'm gonna stack it into a word column, tfidf column, and
然后分开储存到word 和tf-idf这两列
now I'm gonna sort it in descending order.
并且降序排序
So from highest to lowest.
从最高到最低
And if you remember, just before we run this.
如果你记住的话 在我们运行之前
When we did it for just word count you look like this.
在我们之前对单词计数做了类似的事
There was the most popular word, then in, then and, then of,
最普遍的单词就是then in and of 这些
then to, his, then Obama, act, a, and he.
然后就是to his Obama act a he这些单词
So those words are mostly uninformative except for the word Obama.
这些单词通常不包含什么特殊的信息 除了Obama（奥巴马）这个单词
So let's execute it for TF-IDF.
让我们对TF-IDF执行它
And what we see here, voila, the most informative word is Obama
我们可以看到 最具有信息的单词就是奥巴马
which makes a lot of sense because the article is about him.
这也很合理 因为整篇文章都是有关奥巴马的
But then you have art, Iraq, control, law, ordered,
然后剩下的就是art Iraq control law 依次排序 （艺术 伊拉克 控制 法律）
military, involvement, response, democratic, as in Democratic Party.
military involvement response democratic 和 democratic party（军师 参与 回应 民主 民主党）
So you see, lots of action going on here around
你可以看到单词
words that are important, with respect to Obama.
都和奥巴马的活动有着重要的联系
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community